MICHAEL COLEMAN

(512) 620-2243

michaelbrentcoleman@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mc2243/

SUMMARY

Business Intelligence Data Analyst

An experienced financial and data analyst with ability to provide data models for data visualization, analytics, and reporting. Proficient with leveraging tools and technologies to tell stories and solve complex problems with data. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills, able to effectively collaborate in a team and contribute within an Agile development engineering framework. Quick learner, professional, creative, and fun to work with even in high-stress environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Excel
- SQL
- Python
- Rstudio
- Jupyter notebooks
- Machine Learning

- Deep Learning
- Data Mining
- Spreadsheets
- Workbooks
- **Formulas**
- Methodology

- Big Data
- Github
- **Basic Statistics**
- **Data Modeling**

BUSINESS SKILLS

- Financial & Data Analysis
- **Effective Professional Communication**
- Cross-Team Collaboration
- Conflict Resolution & Team Building
- Organized, Able to Prioritize, Meet Deadlines

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Analyzed a loan request as part of a Capstone team project, using Excel for statistical analysis and Pivot Tables for data visualization to improve company strategy by decreasing variable costs by more than 20%.
- Created a business plan for setting up a private clinic to treat head lice. Presented plan for efficacy, advantages, and staff education at about 12 schools. The results of the business plan would minimize staff risk by about 35% while preventing lost revenue due to absenteeism.
- Developed and submitted a proposal concerning seniority at UPS that would resolve conflicts with the Union and reduce stress and conflict with upper management by at least 50%.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Personal Shopper Walmart, CA Dec 2019-Nov 2023

- Coordinated and managed online orders for pickup or delivery.
- Adhered to guidelines and protocols, including proper handling of items.
- Maintained cleanliness and organization of shopping areas and storage space.

Data Science

Data Visualization

- Provided excellent customer service, addressing questions or concerns.
- Initiated good communication skills to interact with customers and team members.
- Demonstrated an ability to work in a fast-paced environment and manage multiple tasks.
- Gained proficiency with online order systems and communication tools.
- Exhibited physical stamina to stand, walk, and lift items for extended periods.

Timekeeper Franchise Tax Board, CA Jan 2019-July 2019

- Created, tracked, and maintained timesheets in the Technology Services Division
- Answered oral and written inquiries from customers and colleagues.
- Maintained communication log via email.
- Typed memos and correspondence for agents and managers, listings, list files.
- Provided records retention.
- Utilized Office Suite of programs comprising Excel, Word, Outlook.

Office Manager

Lice Clinics of America, CA

July 2016-Dec 2018

- As a Subject Matter Expert, answered oral and written inquiries from clients and members of the public.
- Constructed email list with individualized marketing strategy.
- Created database of treatment with corresponding memos and correspondence
- Asset allocation and management

Enrollment Counselor

Western Governors University, TX

May 2013-May 2016

- Performed wide variety of administrative tasks.
- Answered phone, email, and written inquiries.
- Offered a student-centered relational approach.
- Provided program assessment, advising, planning, and marketing.
- Ran analysis of variables and presentation of alternatives.
- Utilized Office Suite of programs comprising Excel, Word, Outlook, PowerPoint, and Salesforce.

Office Manager

Sacramento Turn Verein, CA

Apr 2006-Apr 2009

- Managed and conducted business operations of 35,000 sq ft building.
- Managed Hall rental and office support; marketing, promotion, sales.
- Effectively collaborated with internal stakeholders in planning and promotion of private and community events
- Gained knowledge of contracts; secure, document, and post financial transactions.
- Defined, disclosed, and discussed relevant policy.
- Onboarded, trained, and supervised event staff.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

MBA Management & Strategy, Western Governors University

Data Analysis (Entry-Level), New Horizons

Microsoft Office Specialist: Excel (Office 2016)